

Abhishek Upadhyay

Dafa Scientist



Professional Summary

Well-qualified Data Scientist experienced in working with vast data sets to break down information, gather relevant points and solve advanced business problems. Skilled in Machine Learning, Data Visualization ,Stats , SQL and Python. Offering 4 years of experience in improving business operations.



Work History

2018-03 -2019-09

Data Scientist

Bloomberg LP, Princeton, NJ

Spearheaded development for suite of Business Intelligence apps for all firm wide executives applying Machine Learning and Data Visualization.

 Collaborated with internal stakeholders, identifying and gathering analytical requirements for customer, product and projects needs

 Build dashboards to serve across all business areas providing analytics to influence firms strategic planning and executives' decision-makina

and executives' decision-making
Predicted with 95% accuracy Bloomberg's Global Data headcount (FTE) using time series forecasting by applying machine learning with linear regression and TBATS (ARIMA) in python

Applied statisfical analysis and Hypothesis A/B testing

 Managed Machine Learning projects laying the road map, data gathering, preparation, feature engineering, models selection and deployment

 Reduced load times to 75% by redesigning Data warehouse architecture

2014-07 -2016-07

Data Warehouse Engineer

BNP Paribas, Mumbai, India

Led the Application development for Valuation & Risk Control of Trades in Equities and Fixed Income.

Decreased process time by 50% applying indexing optimization in SQL



Education

2016-08 -2017-12

Master of Science: Management Information Systems

Carnegie Mellon University (CMU) - Pittsburgh, PA

• Graduated with 3.5/4.0 GPA

2017-06 -2017-07

Summer Institute of General Management: Business Management

Stanford Graduate School of Business - Palo Alto, CA

• Won the Dean's award for Excellence

2010-08 -2014-06

Bachelor of Engineering: Computer Science

University of Mumbai - Mumbai, India

Graduated with 3.43/4.0 GPA



Address

30 Newport Parkway Jersey City, NJ, 07030

Phone

(412) 983-3173

E-mail

abhimba1992@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/abhishekupadhyay92/



Machine Learning: (Time Series Forecasting, Regression, Classification, Clustering and PCA)

Very Good

Advanced Machine Learning: (Neural networks, SVM, random forests, bagging, gradient boosting machines, k-means and deep learning)

Very Good

Data Visualization: (QlikSense, Tableau and matplotlib)

Very Good

SQL

Excellent

Python: (Pandas, Numpy and Sklearn)

Excellent

Statistics



Project Management: (Agile, Jira and MS Project)



Programming: R, Java , HTML and UNIX



Data Science Tools: (Git, Jupyter Notebook and Eclipse)





Achievements

 Black Belt - Karate Budokan Institute, March 2019

 Won Bronze Medal at Malaysian Open in Karate 20 National - 8 Gold, 6 Silver and 6 Bronze medals

 President of Students Council at University of Mumbai, 2014